Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 1. Reel-to-Reel audio tape, 1934 - 1981; 1; Boxes: 1744 - 1818
  - Subseries 1.5: Flight to Adventure, 1955 - 1960; 1.5; Boxes: 1759 - 1765
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1957 (Folder 1760.15, Box 1760)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1957 (Folder 1760.16, Box 1760)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1957 (Folder 1760.17, Box 1760)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1957 (Folder 1760.18, Box 1760)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1957 (Folder 1761.01, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1957 (Folder 1761.02, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1957 (Folder 1761.03, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1957 September 6 (Folder 1761.04, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1957 September 6 (Folder 1761.05, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, sound effects: Timbuktu - Camels, 1957 November 1 (Folder 1761.06, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Hawaii, 1957 (Folder 1761.07, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1957 (Folder 1761.08, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from North Pole, 1957 (Folder 1761.09, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from North Pole, 1957 (Folder 1761.10, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1957 (Folder 1761.11, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1957 (Folder 1761.12, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1957 (Folder 1761.13, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1957 (Folder 1761.14, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa - Timbuktu, 1957 (Folder 1761.15, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa, 1957 (Folder 1761.16, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa - Timbuktu, 1957 (Folder 1761.17, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa - Timbuktu, 1957 (Folder 1761.18, Box 1761)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Morocco, 1957 (Folder 1762.01, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1957 (Folder 1762.02, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Lowell Thomas en route to Australia, 1957 (Folder 1762.03, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Lowell Thomas en route to Australia, 1957 (Folder 1762.04, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska - Hawaii, circa 1957 (Folder 1762.05, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, circa 1957 (Folder 1762.06, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Hawaii, 1958 (Folder 1762.07, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Hawaii - Danger Island, circa 1958 (Folder 1762.08, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Hawaii - Danger Island, circa 1958 (Folder 1762.09, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Danger Island, 1958 (Folder 1762.10, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Danger Island, 1958 (Folder 1762.11, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Danger Island, 1958 (Folder 1762.12, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Danger Island -Zanzibar, 1958 October 27 - December 9 (Folder 1762.13, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Saudi Arabia, 1958 (Folder 1762.14, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Zanzibar, 1958 (Folder 1762.15, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa - Semliki, 1958 (Folder 1762.16, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa - Semliki -Arabia - East Africa, 1958 (Folder 1762.17, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa, 1958 (Folder 1762.18, Box 1762)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa - Zanzibar, 1958 (Folder 1763.01, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Arabia - Africa - Congo, 1958 (Folder 1763.02, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Africa - Congo, 1958 (Folder 1763.03, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Arabia - Semliki, 1958 (Folder 1763.04, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Arabia - Africa, 1958 (Folder 1763.05, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Indochina - Arabia, 1958 (Folder 1763.06, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Morocco, 1958 (Folder 1763.07, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Morocco, circa 1958 (Folder 1763.08, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Hawaii, 1958 (Folder 1763.09, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Hawaii - Japan, 1958 (Folder 1763.10, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Japan, 1958 (Folder 1763.11, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Japan, 1958 (Folder 1763.12, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Japan - Arabia, 1958 (Folder 1763.13, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska - Hawaii - Japan, 1958 (Folder 1763.14, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Asia - Indochina, 1958 (Folder 1763.15, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1958 (Folder 1763.16, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1958 (Folder 1763.17, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska - Hawaii, 1958 (Folder 1763.18, Box 1763)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1958 (Folder 1764.01, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1958 (Folder 1764.02, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1958 (Folder 1764.03, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1958 (Folder 1764.04, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1958 (Folder 1764.05, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1958 (Folder 1764.06, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1959 (Folder 1764.07, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1959 (Folder 1764.08, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, 1959 (Folder 1764.09, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Equatorial Africa, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.10, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.11, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Japan, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.12, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.13, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.14, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.15, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.16, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.17, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from Alaska, circa 1957 - 1959 (Folder 1764.18, Box 1764)
    - “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea, 1960 August 23 (Folder 1765.01, Box 1765)
  - Subseries 1.6: Lowell Thomas radio inserts, 1934 - 1963; 1.6; Boxes: 1769 - 1773
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1934 January 3 (Folder 1769.01, Box 1769)
      Montmartre
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1949 July - August (Folder 1769.02, Box 1769)
      From the Pacific 1. Lowell Thomas program, Hawaii, interview with Duke Kahanamoku, July 29, 1949 2. Lowell Thomas regarding Wake Island, August 1 1949 3. Lowell Thomas from Tokyo, impressions of city, August 3, 1949 4. Lowell Thomas from Tokyo, report on visit with emperor and story of Colonel Wheeler, August 4, 1949
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1953 July 13 (Folder 1769.03, Box 1769)
      Lowell Thomas for Kaiser Motors (Anc. Henry Hamilton) (Lowell Thomas laughs) Aired on CBS
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1953 July 31 (Folder 1769.04, Box 1769)
      1. Original 2. 6:45 - 7:00 3. 11:30 - 11:45 p.m. 4. Runs 1:45
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1955 (Folder 1769.05, Box 1769)
      2) Native Singer; 3) Singer; 4) Singer; 5) S.E. over wooden bridge; recorded in Kalimati, Kathmandu, Nepal on Magnetite by Amplicorp.
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1956 November 21 (Folder 1769.06, Box 1769)
      1. General Albert C. Wedemeyer 2. Cripple Creek 3. Tiger Hunt 4. Gaur Hunt 5. Tenth Division 6. Spec. Introduction (Lee) Recorded at Pawling, New York on Bell & Howell
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1960 (Folder 1769.07, Box 1769)
      (Prosper B) Lowell Thomas for Olds Regular program Contains mention of Prosper
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1962 August 16 (Folder 1769.08, Box 1769)
      1. Hoover 2. Without commercial
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 June 4 (Folder 1769.09, Box 1769)
      Lowell Thomas 50 Rockefeller Plaza To Mary Davis and Gene Nicks 3 subjects: Ceylon, flight to Australia, arrival in Central New Guinea
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 June 6 (Folder 1769.10, Box 1769)
      New Guinea Tapes number 1
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 June 24 (Folder 1769.11, Box 1769)
      New Guinea, number 11 1. Reel 11 2. Opens - “Hi Dick - Hello everybody” 3. Closes - “…they are as tough and as rugged as anybody. S’long”
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 September (Folder 1769.12, Box 1769)
      1. Ret. Pole 1963; September 19; Gill, September 20; McCord, September 23; Cars, September 24; Refugees, September 25; Skipper, September 26; Cowboy, September 27; French river, September 30
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 October 24-25 (Folder 1769.13, Box 1769)
      1. Darwin 5 and 6 2. Linkletter salute 3. Pearls 4. Snaggle-toothed Sal
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 December 20 (Folder 1769.14, Box 1769)
      1. Gene: These are 3 more to use Christmas week 2. King Zahir Shah - 3 minutes, 10 seconds 3. Buzkashi tournament number 1 - 2 minutes, 50 seconds 4. Buzkashi tournament number 2 - 3 minutes, 27 seconds
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 (Folder 1769.15, Box 1769)
      1. Stone age man, June 9, 1963 2. Roberts College, May 24, 1963 3. Shah, May 63 4. Goa, May 15,1963 5. Mid-East, May 27, 1963 6. Taj-Nashville, May 29, 1963
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 (Folder 1769.16, Box 1769)
      New Guinea, number 1 1. Reel 1 2. Take to Salzburg
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 (Folder 1769.17, Box 1769)
      New Guinea, number 2 1. Reel 2
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 (Folder 1769.18, Box 1769)
      New Guinea, number 3 Reel 3
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1964 September 29 (Folder 1770.01, Box 1770)
      from Cape Town 1. Polar flight South Africa to Cape Town 2. Pre-flight recording 3. Flight date Monday, September 29, 1964 4. For air on CBS
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1965 January (Folder 1770.02, Box 1770)
      East Africa 1965 1. Reel number 2 2. Cuts 1 to 9 3. Hillary - January 20, 1965 4. Mecca/Medina - January 21, 1965 5. Kilimanjaro - January 22, 1965 6. Lake Manyara - January 25, 1965 7. Ngorongoro Crater - January 26, 1965 8. Cornell Grad - Dick Estes - January 27, 1965 9. Martin and Osa Johnson - January 28, 1965 10. Dick and Nancy Warren - January 29, 1965 11. Auto Accident - February 1, 1965
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1965 February 2-11 (Folder 1770.03, Box 1770)
      East Africa 1965 1. Reel number 3 2. Cuts 1 to 8 3. Price and Booth 4. Price and Booth 5. B-1 treetops 6. B-3 treetops 7. C-1 treetops 3 8. C-2 treetops 4 9. Kenya 10. Ethiopia
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1965 (Folder 1770.04, Box 1770)
      East Africa 1965 1. Reel number 1 2. Tnx. to script
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1965 (Folder 1770.05, Box 1770)
      East Africa 1965 1. Reel number 4 2. Cuts 1 to 6 3. Ethiopia 4. Aden 5. Shereef Hussein [Sharif Hussein] 6. Burma 7. Sukarno 8. Chus. Banfe (not used on air 9. Recorded in Tokyo
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1965 (Folder 1770.06, Box 1770)
      Edited “East Africa” 1965 Tape number 2 1. Edited copy 2. Taken from program inserts used on program during trip 3. CBS network for General Motors Corporation-Fisher
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1965 (Folder 1770.07, Box 1770)
      Edited “East Africa” 1965 Tape number 3 1. Edited copy 2. Taken from program inserts used during trip
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1965 (Folder 1770.08, Box 1770)
      edited - “East Africa” 1965 1. Taken from program inserts during trip
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 May 9-18 (Folder 1770.09, Box 1770)
      inserts from program. /c Townsend (Lt in London), 8 pieces (3 unused) air over CBS May 9-13, 1966 (Dewey; All American; Hussein; Monastery; Prim Man; Other World; Sub: Airplanes number 1) Monday May 9, 1966, “Dewey Book” 01:37 number 2) Tuesday May 10, 1966, “All American” 01:44 number 3) Wednesday May 11, 1966 “King Hussein” 02:08 number 4) Thursday May 12, 1966, “Monastery” 01:46 number 5) Friday May 13, 1966, “Primitive Man” 02:18 number 6) Monday May 16, 1966, “Other Worlds” 01:35 - not used number 7) Tuesday May 17, 1966, “Subways” 01:40 - not used number 8) Wednesday May 18, 1966, “Acropolis” 01:35 - not used
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 May 9-18 (Folder 1770.10, Box 1770)
      CBS that ref. to London original be cut per Salant and FCC inserts from program. /c Townsend (LT in London), 8 pieces (3 unused) air over CBS 5/9-13/66 (This is unabridged version prior to demand by 1) “Dewey Book” - May 9, 1966 - 01:37 2) “All American” - May 10, 1966 - 01:44 3) “King Hussein” - May 11, 1966 - 02:08 4) “Monastery” - May 12, 1966 - 01:46 5) “Primitive Man” - May 13, 1966 - 02:18 6) “Other Worlds” - May 16, 1966 - 01:35 - not used 7) “Subways” - May 17, 1966 - 01:40 - not used 8) “Acropolis” - May 18, 1966 - 01:35 - not used Note: Times shown may change somewhat on “air copy” due to cuts demanded by CBS, namely all mention of London originations (teeny weeny minds and pretentious punks)
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 August 12, 24 D (Folder 1770.11, Box 1770)
      1. Basutoland, M.I.T., Traesyre, Church, St. Barbe 2. Subways 3. Redwoods
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 October (Folder 1770.12, Box 1770)
      inserts on program while in Europe 1. Boris 2. Fall 3. Skirts 4. Petra 5. Geographics Alaska 6. Almanac 7. Death Valley 8. Whale 9. Femme Fatale 10. Bet and Beth 11. Fitness 12. As recorded (cut for air) 13. Transcribed from Norelco cartridge October 1966
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 October (Folder 1770.13, Box 1770)
      inserts used on CBS Radio while in Europe 1. 12 pieces in the sequence aired 2. Boris 3. Fall 4. Skirts 5. Petra 6. Geographic 7. Between Jerusalem and Bethlehem 8. Death Valley and Art Linkletter 9. Femme Fatale 10. Alaska 11. Almanac 12. Fitness 13. Whale
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 December 4 (Folder 1770.14, Box 1770)
      sent to Mr. Dewar McCormack 1. South African Broadcasting Corporation 209 Beach Road Sea Point, Cape Town, South Africa 2. (Alaska)
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 December 7-30 (Folder 1770.15, Box 1770)
      Inserts for program while in London and Alaska. 12 pieces at 7.5 inches per second December 1966. Townsend sub on CBS Radio. December 7 “Reasoner” 1:30 © December 8 “Tibet” 2:03 (S) December 9 “Almanac” 1:19 © December 12 “Fitness” 1:32 (S) December 13 “Whale” 1:31 © December 14 “Abu Dhabi” 2:15 (S) December 15 “Gold Mine” 1:28 © December 16 “John Jay” 1:45 (S) December 22 “Salmon” 1?58 (S) December 26 “Dam” 2:03 (S) December 28 “South Pacific” 1:32 (S) December 30 “Nubas” 2:03 (S)
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 December 30 (Folder 1770.16, Box 1770)
      Lowell Thomas on mountain climbing 1. As piped from Anchorage for insert on regular program 2. Edited for air by CBS
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1966 (Folder 1770.17, Box 1770)
      Interviews St. Barbe Baker, “man of the trees” Attempt to re-forestation June 1966
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1968 (Folder 1770.18, Box 1770)
      “Olympics ‘68” 1. Atwater-Avalanche 2. Duke Kahanamoku 3. Malta 4. Valentine Day 5. Aswan 6. Vatican
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1969 March 13 (Folder 1771.01, Box 1771)
      Used while in Norway and at points in Europe 1. Sled dogs (ski-do) 2. Gold 3. Abu Dhabi Dallas Townsend loco temens
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1970 (Folder 1771.02, Box 1771)
      Thomas Spots Recorded 6/1/70 For Electra 6 shows
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, circa 1971 July (Folder 1771.03, Box 1771)
      1. Nome nugget - 1:16 2. Wewak, New Guinea - 1:36 3. Tibet - 1.37 4. Travelling Romans - 1:28 5. Lindbergh - 1:04 6. Tattooing - 1:05 7. Bagpipes - 1:53 8. The Wolf - 1:30 9. Sailing ship Yankee - 2:00 10. Maine towns - 1:24 11. Space - 1:04 12. Star Cirius - 1:15 13. Citrus - 1:05
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1971 October 29 (Folder 1771.04, Box 1771)
      8 pieces, Dembo original feed from Rome
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1971 October (Folder 1771.05, Box 1771)
      Made at Pawling October 8, 1971 8 shows - for London, Paris trip, October 14, 1971
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1971 November (Folder 1771.06, Box 1771)
      story of 80 year old man
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1972 January 10 (Folder 1771.07, Box 1771)
      Radio Inserts: 1. American Campus Morals; Liberty Magazine 2. Think Tank 3. Oil in Alaska’s North Slope 4. Early Planes; Metal-skinned aircraft 5. Morgantown People Mover, West Virginia 6. Greater Bird of Paradise, New Guinea 7. Filming in Nepal; Hotel Everest View, 12,600ft 8. Saint Barr Baker, limited timber and Fossil Fuels 9. Cannibals, Goodyear Blimp [same as 1840.13] 10. Australian Aborigines Demonstrate 11. Bob Trumble, Australia; Pidgin English 12. Teaching Soccer to New Guinea cannibals 13. Tahiti Expedition to find Von Luckner’s ship 14. Everything You Always Wanted to Know About the USA and Then Some 15. Nixon in China; South America, Venezuela Oil Boom 16. Caracas 15 years later; Angel Falls 17. Brazil
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1972 February - April (Folder 1771.08, Box 1771)
      1st 5 pieces of Lowell Thomas South America tour in Feb 1972 3 pieces of South America tour made during Western trip in March 1972 2 pieces made for Lowell Thomas birthday in Orlando April 6, 1972 Afghanistan and Papua
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1972 October 30 -November 10 (Folder 1771.09, Box 1771)
      Date Time Content 10/30/72 1:53 Plant a Tree - Yellowstone Park 10/31/72 2:33 Lord Mountbatten - with station plug 11/1/72 1:19 Beverly Mims 11/2/72 1:19 H.L. Hunt 11/3/72 1:17 Wingate Lawrence 11/6/72 1:19 Kathmandu - Nepal 11/7/72 1:24 Greek Thesaurus 11/8/72 1:48 Football 11/9/72 1:45 Explorers 11/10/72 1:19 A Century of Progress
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1972 (Folder 1771.10, Box 1771)
      1. 12/25 Katzenjammer Kids 2. 12/27 Sweet Adeline 3. 12/28 Elephants
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1973 January 9 (Folder 1771.11, Box 1771)
      Flying the Atlantic insert on Morley Safer, Lowell Thomas insert (sick)
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts (Folder 1771.12, Box 1771)
      1. For period April 3 1973 - April 10 1973
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1973 September 24-26 (Folder 1771.13, Box 1771)
      Used during Lake Placid trip - Hong Kong, iceberg, fish
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1973 December 28-31 (Folder 1771.14, Box 1771)
      inserts during Hawaii Trip December 2-31, air time: January 8, 1974 Lowell Thomas inserts for New Year’s Weekend Date Name of Show Time 12/28/73 Rube Goldberg 1:47 12/31/73 UFO 2:00 1/1/74 Canadian G. Sinclair 4:40 1/2/74 Emperor Young Lo 1:18 1/3/74 Montmartre 1:20 1/4/74 Doctor Luehring 1:15 1/7/74 Badgers 1:17 1/8/74 Rhino 1:25 Tapes for the above periods are located on shelf in Tape Locker in BOD area.
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1973 December 31 (Folder 1771.15, Box 1771)
      U.F.O.
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1973 (Folder 1771.16, Box 1771)
      1. Cripple Creek - Charles Finn 2. Cripple Creek 3. Leaning Tower of Pisa 4. Backgammon 5. Morro Castle 6. Hawaiian Crater 7. Father Ross 8. Hail Alley 9. Fish For July 1973 programs
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1974 January 4 (Folder 1771.17, Box 1771)
      Doctor Luehring
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1974 January 7 (Folder 1771.18, Box 1771)
      Badgers
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1974 July - August 22 (Folder 1772.01, Box 1772)
      1. Opening and closing, sfx and promo 2. 2385 Golf courses 3. Unusual golf 4. Nat Reed - to many of us 5. New York elephant hunt 6. Alaskan pipeline 7. “ “ 8. “ “ 9. “ “ 10. Goldmine in sea - Hawaii 11. Alaska gold mining 12. North Pole controversy
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, circa 1974 (Folder 1772.02, Box 1772)
      To Gene To be used during travels Miscellaneous, India, Madagascar and more 1. The Stars 2. Snoring 3. Bicentennial 4. Importing African animals 5. Australia treasure hunters 6. India, last battle of the Revolutionary War 7. […] Island 8. Istanbul, Arthur Watson, IBM 9. Bedouin nomads 10. Zulu resistance 11. Madagascar 12. Vacation castle in Europe (1970)
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, undated (Folder 1772.03, Box 1772)
      1. Tape insert used on regular program 2. Reports on Communists and India 3. Dalai Lama mention only
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, undated (Folder 1772.04, Box 1772)
      July 21: [San Francisco?] urban waste number 2 [#1?] Professor F. Davis, Urban Waste, recycling solution; useful metals and glass; “Urban Ore”
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, undated (Folder 1772.05, Box 1772)
      July 21 About Major Jimmy Stahlman, retiring Nashville Banner Editor; pronunciation mistakes by Lowell Thomas
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, undated (Folder 1772.06, Box 1772)
      Inserts during Iceland Trip Mushroom hunting, no way to tell if edible; Harold Macmillan, former British Prime Minister; Gary Powers U-2 flight; Kelp’s speedy growth, California Kelp crop wiped out by sea urchins because rarity of otters; Athletic health; General Abraham [Joffe?] extinctions in Israel
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, undated (Folder 1772.07, Box 1772)